

PROFILE

A highly skilled frontend developer, crafting exceptional web experiences using React and TypeScript with great passion. Over 3 years, gaining skills have been honed to deliver performant, user-friendly, and visually appealing web applications.

Beyond coding, excelled in collaborative environments, embracing challenges, and always trying to stay at the forefront of web development trends.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91-9567794351

GITHUB: github.com/shivaramr

gitnub.com/snivai

https://youtube.com/channel/UCNds RZ_aNFDVCrnAgNnxBRw

EMAIL:

shivaramr.mec@gmail.com

SKILLS

YOUTUBE:

ReactJS NodeJS NextJS TypeScript HTML/CSS/SCSS

R SHIVARAM

Frontend Developer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Benchmark Estimating, Frontend Developer

March 2023-Present

Developing user interfaces for a project to help organizations in controlling costs, resources and carbon emissions, for efficient and green future. The project gives a great exposure and makes a significant difference for the society. Received several appreciations from the team and progressing to achieve greatness.

Urja Global, Technical Architect/Software Engineer

January 2023–February 2023

Designed and executed an efficient ERP website for an upcoming edtech organization, to manage resources and educational information.

Aurum Proptech, Software Engineer

August 2022-December 2022

Contributed in building an e-commerce website for the real estate domain to one of the top organizations from the country to help users in buying, selling, and reselling of real estate of several reputed real estate. Also, developed, two other websites for admin monitoring and developer lead generation dashboards.

Sedai, Software Engineer

October 2021-February 2022

Developed user interfaces for a product that eases the work of SREs of top companies in maintaining their cloud storage, memory allocation and cost management, mainly in the amazon cloud (lambda).

Kimball Electronics, Software Engineer

August 2020-September 2021

Developed user interfaces and server-side APIs for an industry 4.0 product that processes information and helps in achieving industrial automation. The project is a huge success and is used by several factories across the globe. Grateful and proud to share the opportunity received for developing base template in the backend, several UI pages and CICD configurations individually.

HOBBIES

Bike Rides Traveling Watching Premier League Playing FIFA

PROJECTS

Weather App,

NextJS, Typescript, Material UI

The project was developed to delve into Next.js, this weather application utilizes the Open Weather API. Leveraging useContext and useReducer hooks, for efficiently managed states, resulting in a fully mobile responsive website. Utilized Next.js features for simplified page creation and improved project organization. Uploaded to GitHub for accessibility. View the deployed result at Weather App. Demo can be viewed at Weather App Youtube demo. Uploaded to GitHub for easy reference.

Al Summarizer,

Vite, React, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS

The project utilizes AI to summarize user-provided URLs. Developed by integrating rapid API services for article extraction. Gained insights into React-based Vite projects, recognizing their growing importance. View the deployed result at <u>AI Summarizer</u>. Demo can be viewed at <u>AI Summarizer</u> uploaded to GitHub for easy reference.

Resume Maker, React, formik, pdfMake

This small project features a user-friendly interface where users can input data step by step. The submitted data is then gathered and transformed into a PDF format. It utilizes the Formik library for form handling in the interface and pdfMake for creating PDF documents. The project is uploaded in Git profile, and a demonstration can be viewed at Resume Maker Demo.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering, Govt. Model Engineering College, Thrikakkara

August 2016 - September 2020

Held several leadership roles like Vice Chairman of IETE, Co-founder of MEC.Conf and passed with a GPA of 7.55, being an all-round role-model to juniors.

HSC, Kendriya Vidyalaya No.2, Naval Base, Kochi-04

April 2004 – June 2016

Completed schooling from one of the top 6 government schools of the country, fulfilling commanding opportunities received to the best and with GPA of 9.2 in SSC and 86% in HSC.

REFERENCES

Albert CY

Technical Lead, Infosys, johanein@gmail.com

Marshall Cheneval

Development Programs Manager, Benchmark Estimating, marhsall.cheneval@benchmarkestimating.com